Finding Aid for Michigan Land Use Institute records, 1995-2007
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Michigan Land Use Institute records
1995-2007
Michigan Land Use Institute.
07144 Bn 2
Records of the Michigan Land Use Institute, a northern-Michigan based environmental and regional planning organization. The Institute uses local programming and local and statewide political lobbying to establish an approach to economic and physical development that strengthens communities, limits suburban sprawl, and protects Michigan’s natural resources. This record group contains correspondence, reports, conference papers, and publications related to the organization and its goals.
47 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Materials were donated to the library in July of 2007 by the Michigan Land Use Institute (donor no. 9102 ).
Periodic additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
Keith Schneider started the Michigan Land Use Institute in 1995 as an outgrowth of the Michigan Communities Land Use Coalition, a small, all-volunteer grassroots organization based out of Manistee County. The organization's founding document indicates that the goal of the Michigan Land Use Institute is to safeguard the land and life of northwest Michigan through managing population growth, natural resource and agricultural policies, and the negative environmental impact of suburban sprawl in northwest Michigan. Mr. Schneider and the founding board of the Institute established an office in Beulah, Michigan and hired a full time staff of experts in areas such as land use planning, sustainable agriculture, waste management, energy efficiency, education, and public policy to design programs and policies to address these issues. The organization's focus has broadened throughout its existence to include addressing these and similar issues on a statewide as well as local level.
In 2000 Keith Schneider stepped down from the role of Executive Director to take on the position of the Director of Program Development, and, in 2003, the additional role of deputy director of the institute. Hans Voss took over the role of Executive Director in 2000 and under his directorship the Institute has expanded considerably, establishing regional offices in Lansing, Grand Rapids, Harbor Springs, and Traverse City and becoming one of the largest state-based environmental and land use policy advocacy organizations in the country.
Since its inception, the Institute has sought to become a resource for other community organizations through conducting research, amassing a library of conservation and land use related material, publishing reports and pamphlets on these issues, and conducting seminars and workshops for community groups. They have also implemented a number of community programs, including the Michigan Land Stewardship Program, the Transportation and Land Use Initiative, New Entrepreneurial Agriculture Program, the Michigan Energy Reform Coalition, the Public Trust Alliance, and the Grassroots Support Center.
The Michigan land Use Institute Records contain materials dating from the Institute's inception in 1995 through 2006 and originating from a number of different offices and administrative units. The collection has been divided into five series, Legal, Library, Policy Files, Program Files, and Visual and Electronic Materials.
Subjects:
Boardman River Valley (Mich.); Cities and towns--Growth--Michigan.; City planning--Michigan.; Environmental protection--Michigan.; Grand Traverse County (Mich.); Highway bypasses--Michigan--Traverse City.; Land use--Michigan--Planning.; Michigan Land Use Institute.; Transportation and state--Michigan.; Traverse City (Mich.)--Economic conditions.; Water resources development--Michigan.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Land use--Michigan.; Michigan Land Use Institute.; Traverse City (Mich.)
Genre Terms:
Videotapes.; Photographs.
- Legal
  The Legal series contains legal briefs, case notes, Freedom of Information Act requested documents, and correspondence relating to a number of land use legal cases in northern Michigan.
  - Great Lakes Oil and Gas Drilling
    - Coastal Ordinance (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 1)
    - Drain Code, 1999 (Box 1)
    - Federal Code and Regulations, 1998 (Box 1)
    - FOIA Requests, 1997 (Box 1)
    - FOIA Responses, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Newstar Energy, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
    - Oil and Gas Drilling Moratorium, 1998-2000 (Box 1)
    - Oil and Gas Information, 1998-2000 (Box 1)
  - Jordan Valley
    - Jordan Valley, 1997-2006 (Box 1)
    - Review of Application to PSC, 1998-2006 (Box 1)
    - Petition of Walter Zaremba, 1997-2006 (Box 1)
    - Press Release, 1997 (Box 1)
    - PSC/Zaremba Application, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Minden Bog
    - Minden Bog, General, 1995-1999; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Consolidation Binder (Box 1)
    - Articles, 1998-1999 (Box 1)
    - Barbara J. Madsen Information, 1995 (Box 2)
    - FOIA Requests, 1998 (Box 2)
    - Legal, 1995-1998 (Box 2)
    - Project Proposal, 1998 (Box 2)
    - Report, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Petoskey Bypass Transportation Project, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Projects and Board Business, 1995-1996 (Box 2)
    - South Fox Is, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Takings
    - Attorney General's Takings Guidelines, 1998 (Box 2)
    - K&K Construction, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Traverse City Bridge
    - Traverse City Bridge, General, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Traverse City Bridge, General, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Anglers of Boardman River, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Department of Environmental Quality/Department of Natural Resources, 2002-2004; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Expert Opinions, 2002; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Michigan Environmental Protection Act (Box 3)
    - News Articles, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Olson & Bzdoki-Law Firm, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Plaintiff Planning, 2002-2003 (Box 3)
    - State and Federal Lawmakers (Box 3)
  - Weldon Township
    - Weldon Township, 2001 (Box 3)
    - FOIA Response, 2001 (Box 3)
    - List of Studies (Box 3)
    - Zoning Ordinance (Box 3)
- Library
  The Library series includes a number of publications and reports, authored by MLUI as well as other individuals and organizations, that document environmental and land use planning in Michigan. These publications include local zoning codes, materials from conferences organized or attended by MLUI staff members, and reports and publications relating to issues of water quality and use as well as transportation issues and alternatives. The series also includes printed screenshots from the organization's web page as well as a copy of this web page on CD-ROM.
  - City Plans and Zoning Codes
    - City Plans and Zoning Codes (Box 4)
    - City Plans and Zoning Codes (Box 5)
    - City Plans and Zoning Codes (Box 6)
  - Conference Materials
    - Agendas and Other Material Relating to Environmental and Land Use Conferences Held in the State of Michigan (Box 7)
  - Land Use and Regional Planning Materials
    - Land Use and Smart Growth Materials (Box 8)
    - Land Use and Environmental Planning Materials (Box 9)
    - MPSO Trends Futures Reports for Michigan (Box 10)
  - Transportation Materials
    - General Transportation (Box 11)
    - General Transportation (Box 12)
    - Traverse City Bypass (Box 13)
    - Transportation in Detroit (Box 13)
  - Water Resource and Management Materials
    - Boardman River Study (Box 14)
    - Boardman River Study (Box 15)
    - Great Lakes Material (Box 16)
    - Inland Lakes and Rivers (Box 17)
    - Water Quality (Box 17)
    - Wetlands Material (Box 18)
    - Quality of Life Indices (Box 18)
  - Website
    - Printed Screenshots from MLUI Website (Box 19)
- Policy Files
  The Policy Files, 1995-2006, include the records of the Statewide Policy Director, Charlene Crowell; the Policy Director, Arlin Wasserman; Policy Specialist, Mac McClelland; and Transportation Policy Coordinator, Kelly Thayer. Charlene Crowell's files are further subdivided into the subseries Administrative, Historic Preservation, Land Use, Smart Growth Detroit, Transportation Policy and Various Policy Files. Of these, the Smart Growth Detroit subseries, which contains correspondence and meeting minutes relating to the Institute's programs and partnerships aiming to limit sprawl and create more livable communities in Detroit and Southwest Michigan, is particularly notable, as is the Transportation Policy subseries, which includes research into Michigan's transportation policy and various public transit options as well as documenting Ms. Crowell's participation in Michigan's 2003 Transportation Summit. Arlin Wasserman's files include the subseries Oil and Gas Rights and focus on MLUI's successful lobbying efforts to prevent oil and gas drilling in the Great Lakes. This action eventually led to a permanent state ban on such drilling. Mac McClelland's files are broken down into the subseries Community Projects, Fundraising, Michigan Land Use Institute Organization Structure, Michigan Land Use Institute Projects, Neighborhood Schools Projects, and Policy. The most significant of these is the subseries on the Neighborhood Schools Project, a collaboration between MLUI and the Michigan Chamber of commerce that examined the effects of constructing new schools in suburban or rural locations. This project resulted in the introduction of legislation, developed by the Institute, to integrate school location and decisions with local land use mater planning. A further subdivision is the South Haven Schools Project- a project undertaken by board member Joyce Petter, but falling within the scope of the Neighborhood Schools Project. Kelly Thayer's files include numerous miscellaneous files relating to transportation planning and policy and a sub-subseries related to the debate surrounding a proposed plan to reroute traffic in Traverse City, the Traverse City Bypass.
  - Office of the Policy Director-Charlene Crowell
    - Administrative Files
      - Board Letters, 1995-1998 (Box 20)
      - Camp Tosebo, 2005 (Box 20)
      - Conferences, 1999-2005; 2 folders (Box 20)
      - Cyberhood Updates, 2005 (Box 20)
      - Diversity Training, 2005 (Box 20)
      - Election, 2004 (Box 20)
      - Fundraising
        - Annual Campaign, 2004; 2 folders (Box 20)
        - Americana Grant, 2006; 2 folders (Box 20)
        - Development, 2003-2004 (Box 20)
        - Funding Action Team, 2004 (Box 20)
        - Joyce Foundation, 2004 (Box 20)
        - Joyce Report, 2005 (Box 20)
        - MLUI Member and donor Information, 2001 (Box 20)
        - Mott Foundation, 2003-2006; 2 folders (Box 20)
        - Mott Foundation, Eat Fresh, 2006 (Box 20)
        - Mott Foundation Grant, 2006 (Box 20)
        - People and Land (PAL) Grant, 2005 (Box 20)
      - Local Initiatives Support Corporation (LISC)/Ford Project, 2004 (Box 20)
      - LISC/Policy Link, 2004 (Box 20)
      - Megaregions, 2006 (Box 20)
      - Metro-Regional Detroit Investment Initiative (MRDII) Presenters, 2005 (Box 20)
      - Michigan Energy Reform Coalition (MERC) Fact Sheet Originals, 1995-1997 (Box 20)
      - MERC Members, 1999 (Box 20)
      - Michigan Land Use Leadership Council Report, 2003 (Box 20)
      - Meeting Minutes
        - Detroit Transit, May 27, 2005 (Box 20)
        - LISC, February 28, 2005 (Box 20)
        - LISC, March 21, 2005 (Box 20)
        - LISC, April 25, 2005 (Box 20)
        - LISC, November 18, 2005 (Box 20)
        - MLUI Executive Committee Minutes, 1999 (Box 20)
        - MLUI Meeting, March 7, 2005 (Box 20)
        - MLUI Meeting, March 8, 2006 (Box 20)
      - MLUI, 2005 (Box 20)
      - MLUI Administrative, 2004-2005 (Box 20)
      - MLUI Budget, 2006 (Box 20)
      - MLUI Facilities (Box 20)
      - MLUI Project Planning, 2003-2004 (Box 20)
      - MLUI Reports, 2006 (Box 20)
      - MLUI Vendors, 2004 (Box 20)
      - News and Pamphlets, 1997-2001 (Box 20)
      - Wind Energy, 2006 (Box 20)
    - Historic Preservation
      - Allegan, MI, 2003-2004; 2 folders (Box 21)
      - Detroit, 2003 (Box 21)
      - Heritage Tourism in Michigan, 2003 (Box 21)
      - Jackson, MI, 2003; 2 folders (Box 21)
      - Marshall, MI, 2003 (Box 21)
      - Michigan, 2002-2003 (Box 21)
      - Preservation Wayne, 2003 (Box 21)
      - Schools, 2003 (Box 21)
      - State Historic Preservation Office, 2003; 2 folders (Box 21)
    - Land Use
      - Colorado, 2003 (Box 21)
      - Kentucky, 2003 (Box 21)
      - Mary, 2003 (Box 21)
      - Michigan Land Use Leadership Council, 2003; 2 folders (Box 21)
      - New Jersey, 2003 (Box 21)
      - Washington State, 2003 (Box 21)
      - Wisconsin, 2003 (Box 21)
    - Smart Growth Detroit
      - 8 Mile Blvd., 2005 (Box 22)
      - Detroit Area, 2005; 2 folders (Box 22)
      - Detroit PAL, 2003-2004; 3 folders (Box 22)
      - Detroit PAL Proposal, 2004 (Box 22)
      - Detroit Symphony Orchestra, 2004 (Box 22)
      - Detroit Tour, 2004 (Box 22)
      - Greater Corktown, 2005 (Box 22)
      - Habitat for Humanity, 2004 (Box 22)
      - Historic Preservation Awards, 2005 (Box 22)
      - Katz/LISC, 2005 (Box 22)
      - LISC Meeting, 2005 (Box 22)
      - Michigan Economic Development Association, 2006 (Box 22)
      - Michigan State Housing Development Authority, 2006 (Box 22)
      - MRDII Briefing Book, 2004 (Box 22)
      - Northstar CDC, 2005 (Box 22)
      - Northwest Detroit/Redford, 2005 (Box 22)
    - Transportation Policy
      - Amtrak, 2003 (Box 23)
      - American Public Transportation Association, 2004 (Box 23)
      - Context Sensitive Design/Solutions, 2003 (Box 23)
      - Detroit Regional Transportation Alliance, 2005 (Box 23)
      - Detroit Intermodal Freight Terminal, 2005 (Box 23)
      - Donigan, Marie, 2006 (Box 23)
      - Grand Rapids Transit, 2006 (Box 23)
      - Hartman-Hammond Bridge, 2003 (Box 23)
      - Michigan Department of Transportation (MDOT), 2004-2006; 3 folders (Box 23)
      - MDOT Context Sensitive Design, 2005 (Box 23)
      - MDOT Detroit Intermodal Freight Terminal, 2005 (Box 23)
      - Michigan Public Transportation Association, 2004-2005 (Box 23)
      - Michigan Road Builders Association, 2003 (Box 23)
      - Michigan Transportation Bills, 2003 (Box 23)
      - Preserve First, 2005 (Box 23)
      - Railvolution, 2003 (Box 23)
      - Southeast Michigan Council of Governments (SEMCOG), 2005; 2 folders (Box 23)
      - SEMCOG Lawsuit, 2004 (Box 23)
      - STPP, 2004 (Box 23)
      - Transportation Equity Act for the 21st Century (TEA-21), 2004; 2 folders (Box 23)
      - TEA Reauthorization, 2005 (Box 23)
      - Transit, 2004; 2 folders (Box 23)
      - Transit Testimony, 2005 (Box 23)
      - Transportation Coalition, 2003; 4 folders (Box 24)
      - Transportation Coalition, 2004; 3 folders (Box 24)
      - Transportation Coalition, April 6, 2005 (Box 24)
      - Transportation Commission, 2003 (Box 24)
      - Transportation Field Hearings, 2005 (Box 24)
      - Transportation Funding, 2005 (Box 24)
      - Transportation Legislation, 2004 (Box 24)
      - Transportation, Other, 2004 (Box 24)
      - Transportation Research Board, 2005 (Box 24)
      - Transportation Riders United, 2004 (Box 24)
      - Transportation Summit, 2003; 2 folders (Box 24)
    - Various Policy Files
      - Affordable Housing, 2004; 2 folders (Box 25)
      - Allen, Jason, 2006 (Box 25)
      - Agriculture, 2004 (Box 25)
      - America 2050 (Box 25)
      - Ash Institute, 2004 (Box 25)
      - Community Development Corporation of Warren, 2005 (Box 25)
      - Community Economic Development Association of Michigan (CEDAM), 2005 (Box 25)
      - CEDAM Policy Updates, 2005 (Box 25)
      - Clean Michigan Initiative, 2005 (Box 25)
      - Commerce Centers, 2005 (Box 25)
      - Commerce Investment Coalition, 2005 (Box 25)
      - Cool Cities, 2004-2005; 2 folders (Box 25)
      - Conversation on Regional Equity (CORE), 2005 (Box 25)
      - Corridor Improvement Authority Act, 2005 (Box 25)
      - Detroit, 2004 (Box 25)
      - Detroit Area Regional Transit Authority, 2005 (Box 25)
      - Detroit Caucus, 2005 (Box 25)
      - Detroit Chamber, 2005 (Box 25)
      - Detroit Contacts, 2005 (Box 25)
      - Detroit Council, 2004; 2 folders (Box 25)
      - Detroit Edison Energy, 2005 (Box 25)
      - Detroit Lists, 2005 (Box 25)
      - Detroit/Wayne County Port Authority, 2006 (Box 25)
      - Department of Labor and Economic Growth, 2003 (Box 25)
      - Detroit River International Crossing Study, 2006 (Box 25)
      - Environmental Communications and Community Organizing Initiative (ECCO), 2004 (Box 25)
      - Eminent Domain, 2005-2006 (Box 25)
      - Environmental Law and Policy, 2005 (Box 26)
      - Environmental Issues Committee, 2006 (Box 26)
      - Ezekiel Project, 2003 (Box 26)
      - Follow the Money, 2004-2005 (Box 26)
      - Food Policy Council, 2005 (Box 26)
      - Fort/Visger Corridor, 2005 (Box 26)
      - GOP Caucus, 2004 (Box 26)
      - Granholm, 2005 (Box 26)
      - Great Lakes Economic Initiative, 2005 (Box 26)
      - Habitat for Humanity, 2005 (Box 26)
      - Hard Lessons, 2004 (Box 26)
      - House Commerce Committee, 2006 (Box 26)
      - House Government Operations Committee, 2005 (Box 26)
      - Housing, 2006 (Box 26)
      - Housing and Urban Development (HUD), 2005 (Box 26)
      - Incident Reports, 2004-2005 (Box 26)
      - Invitations, 2004 (Box 26)
      - Issue Advocacy, 2006 (Box 26)
      - Jefferson East Business Association (JEBA)/Grosse Pointe, 2005 (Box 26)
      - Land Use Funders, 2005 (Box 26)
      - Legislation
        - Concentrated Animal Feeding Operations (CAFO) Legislation, 2006 (Box 26)
        - House Bill 5479, 2006 (Box 26)
        - Land Use Legislation, 2004 (Box 26)
        - Legislation, 2003-2004; 2 folders (Box 26)
        - Legislative Reports, 2003 (Box 26)
        - Legislative Updates, 2006 (Box 26)
      - LISC, 2004 (Box 26)
      - LISC Budget, 2006 (Box 26)
      - LISC White Pages, 2005 (Box 26)
      - Lobbying Hours, 2004-2007 (Box 26)
      - Mackinac Policy Conference., 2006 (Box 26)
      - Madison Lenox Hotel, 2004-2005 (Box 26)
      - McCotter, Thaddeus (Congressman), 2005 (Box 26)
      - Megapolitics, 2005 (Box 26)
      - Metro Detroit Regional Investment Initiative (MDRII) General Info, 2005 (Box 26)
      - MDRII Lobbying, 2005 (Box 26)
      - Michigan Black Caucus, 2005-2006 (Box 27)
      - Michigan Elected Officials, 2005 (Box 27)
      - Michigan GOP, 2006 (Box 27)
      - Michigan Historic Preservation Network, 2006 (Box 27)
      - Michigan Land Banks, 2006 (Box 27)
      - Michigan Land Use, 2004-2006; 2 folders (Box 27)
      - MLUI Northwest Team, 2006 (Box 27)
      - Michigan State Housing Development Authority (MSHDA), 2004 (Box 27)
      - Michigan State University, 2006; 2 folders (Box 27)
      - MSU Urban Planning (Box 27)
      - Milliken Appeal, 2005 (Box 27)
      - Milwaukee CBA, 2004 (Box 27)
      - MOSES, 2005 (Box 27)
      - Mott Smart Growth, 2004 (Box 27)
      - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP), 2005 (Box 27)
      - National Association of Development Organizations (NADO) Smart Growth, 2005 (Box 27)
      - Neighborhood Enterprise Zones, 2003-2004; 2 folders (Box 27)
      - Pending Issues, 2003-2004 (Box 27)
      - Public Interest Research Group in Michigan (PIRGIM), 2003 (Box 27)
      - Regional Equity Summit, 2005 (Box 27)
      - Results Teams, 2005 (Box 27)
      - Scenic Michigan, 2003 (Box 27)
      - Section 8 Housing, 2004 (Box 27)
      - Small Business Association Loans, 2005 (Box 27)
      - Southeast Michigan Foundations, 2004 (Box 27)
      - Sprawl Related Press Clippings, 2003 (Box 27)
      - State Budget, 2003-2005; 2 folders (Box 27)
      - State of the State, 2004 (Box 27)
      - Strengthening America's Communities Initiative, 2005 (Box 27)
      - Surface Transportation Policy Project, 2006 (Box 27)
      - Transit, 2005-2006; 3 folders (Box 27)
      - Transit-Comprehensive Transportation Fund, 2007 (Box 27)
      - Transit/Michigan Land Use Leadership Coalition, 2005 (Box 27)
      - Urban Redevelopment. (Box 27)
      - Urban Redevelopment Legislation, 2005 (Box 27)
      - Ward, Chris, 2004 (Box 27)
      - Water Policy, 2005-2006; 2 folders (Box 27)
      - Wayne State University, 2005 (Box 27)
  - Office of the Policy Director-Arlin Wasserman
    - Oil and Gas Rights
      - Blue Lakes, 1996-1997 (Box 28)
      - Boardman River, 1997 (Box 28)
      - Formation Leasing, 1997-1998 (Box 28)
      - Hydrogen Sulfide Report, 1993 (Box 28)
      - Hydrogen Sulfide Safety, 1998 (Box 28)
      - Lake Michigan Drilling-Legal, 1997-1999 (Box 28)
      - Lake Michigan Drilling-Ludington State Park, 1997-1999 (Box 28)
      - Lake Michigan Drilling-Michigan Environmental Science Review Board, 1997-1998 (Box 28)
      - Letters from MERC/MLUI, 1995-1998 (Box 28)
      - Ludington, 1997-1999 (Box 28)
      - Ludington State Park Correspondence, 1997 (Box 28)
      - Ludington Park Petition, 2001 (Box 28)
      - Ludington State Park Press Articles, 1997-2000 (Box 28)
      - Manistee County, 1996-1998; 2 folders (Box 28)
      - MERC Position Statements, 1996 (Box 28)
      - MESB Report on Hydrogen Sulfide, 1999 (Box 28)
      - Montmorency County (Box 28)
      - Oil and Gas Leasing, 1982-2005 (Box 28)
      - Oil and Gas Lease Examples, 1987-1992 (Box 28)
      - Pigeon River News clippings, 1996 (Box 28)
      - Pigeon River Notes, 1996-1997 (Box 28)
      - Pigeon River Oil and Gas Production, 2000-2001 (Box 28)
      - Pigeon River Plan Expiration, 1996 (Box 28)
      - Pigeon River Re-Completion, 1998 (Box 28)
      - Pigeon River Sources, 1996-1997 (Box 28)
      - Pigeon River Statistics, 1996 (Box 28)
      - Reports and Drilling News Clippings, 2000-2001 (Box 28)
      - State Documents, 1996-1998 (Box 28)
  - Office of the Policy Specialist-Mac McClelland
    - Community Projects
      - Acme Township, 1999-2003 (Box 29)
      - Chamber Transportation Committee, 2004 (Box 29)
      - Conservation Summit, 2004 (Box 29)
      - Drain Circle, 2000 (Box 29)
      - Empire Schoolhouse Proposal, 2003 (Box 29)
      - Frankfort Affordable Housing (Box 29)
      - Grand Rapids Initiative, 2003 (Box 29)
      - Hartman-Hammond, 2003-2005; 2 folders (Box 29)
      - Leelanau Smart Growth Coalition (Box 29)
      - Traverse City Area School Closing, 2005 (Box 29)
      - Traverse City Parking Access Committee, 2004 (Box 29)
    - Fundraising
      - Annual Campaign, 2003-2004; 2 folders (Box 29)
      - CMP Grants, 2003-2005; 3 folders (Box 29)
      - Fundraising, 2002 (Box 29)
    - Michigan Land Use Institute Organizational Structure
      - Budget Instructions, 2003 (Box 29)
      - Communication Plan, 2004 (Box 29)
      - Communication Training, 2002 (Box 29)
      - Government Structure, 2003 (Box 29)
      - IRS Determination Letter, 1995 (Box 29)
      - Management Information, 2000 (Box 29)
      - Regional Leadership Councils, 2003-2004 (Box 29)
    - Michigan Land Use Institute Projects
      - Entrepreneurial Agriculture Project, 2004 (Box 29)
      - Grassroots Response, 2003 (Box 29)
      - Great Lakes Bulletin, 2003 (Box 29)
      - Great Lakes Policy, 2003 (Box 29)
      - Michigan Land Use Leadership Council, 2003 (Box 29)
      - Northwest Michigan Smart Growth, 2004 (Box 29)
      - Orfield, Myron, 2003 (Box 29)
      - Project Planning, 2004 (Box 29)
      - State Historic Preservation Office Grant Development Project, 2000 (Box 29)
      - State Policy Agenda, 2002; 2 folders (Box 29)
      - Strategic Plan, 2003; 3 folders (Box 29)
    - Neighborhood Schools Project
      - Neighborhood Schools Project, 2003 (Box 29)
      - Case Studies-Michigan, 2000-2001 (Box 29)
      - Case Studies-National, 2001 (Box 29)
      - Clippings, 1998-2004; 4 folders (Box 29)
      - Charlevoix Public Schools, 2003; 2 folders (Box 29)